ADAM ALCANTARA



313 737 1095



adamjalcantara@gmail.com



adamalcantara.com



linkedin.com/in/adam-alcantara



github.com/adamalcantara

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

Adobe Photoshop

CSS

Final Cut Pro X

HTML

JavaScript

Logic Pro X

Squarespace

WordPress

PROFESSIONAL

Dependability

Problem Solving

Critical Thinking

Organization

Creativity

Flexibility

Attention to Detail

PROFILE

Diligent and dedicated jack of all trades who excels at prioritizing, completing tasks efficiently, and customer service. Specializes in photography, videography, and computer troubleshooting, delivering quality results without supervision. Enthusiastic, professional, and always ready for a new challenge.

WORK EXPERIENCE

WALT DISNEY PARKS AND RESORTS

Disney PhotoPass Photographer | January 2016 - Present

- Create memorable interactions with Guests daily using Disney Five Keys Basics; Safety, Courtesy, Show, Efficiency, and Inclusion.
- Selected for specialty trainings in Rover, Magic Words with Mickey, Castle Courtyard, Cinderella's Royal Table Proposal, Photo Support, and Capture Your Moment.
- Rover: Independently seek out quality interactions with Guests while maintaining productivity, exceptional work ethic, and showcasing advanced photography knowledge.
- Photo Support: Provide Cast with tools for success and assist Coordinators and Leadership by communicating technical and daily operational challenges.
- Capture Your Moment: Engaged in personalized photo sessions.
- Effectively communicate and collaborate with multiple lines of business to maintain exceptional Guest service, recovery, and proactively solve unique and multifaceted situations.
- Ensure Cast and Guest safety by providing feedback on Safety in Motion and reporting potential safety concerns.

Disney Photo Imaging Trainer | October 2019 - Present

- Trained incoming Cast Members on Magic Kingdom Park's operations and policies.
- Communicated effective feedback to trainees verbally and with photo reviews to improve photo quality, Guest service, and daily operations.
- Selected as the Opening Team Trainer for Capture Your Moment.
- Assisted in the creation of Creativity Core Training Modules which enhanced department expectations.
- Selected for the Disney PhotoPass Reopening Training team, delivering COVID-19 Safety Critical and Creativity Core training to returning photographers.

ADAM ALCANTARA

AWARDS AND RECOGNITION

Magic Kingdom Diversity and Inclusion Committee Champion 2020

Magic Kingdom Entertainment Quarterly Award Winner

Courtesy Champion of the Month

Magic Kingdom Photo of the Year 2019

Magic Kingdom Photo of the Year 2018

EDUCATION

Ringling College of Art and Design

Some College 2013

Macomb Community
College

Associate's Degree 2021

WORK EXPERIENCE (Continued)

WALT DISNEY PARKS AND RESORTS

Magic Kingdom Park Orientation Facilitator | October 2019 - Present

- Delivered a comprehensive guided tour of Magic Kingdom Park to 20-40 incoming Cast Members to familiarize them with the park layout, locations, and important Magic Kingdom Park information.
- Familiarized Cast Members with local procedures relating to safety, first aid, and security.
- Assist fellow facilitators by supporting the tour, ensuring Facilitator and participant safety, timing accuracy, and partnership with tour stops.

Disney Fine Art Photographer | March 2019 - Present

- Assisted the lead photographer with external details of productions, including time management, travel, equipment, and remained detail oriented during family, bridal, and convention level photo shoots.
- Trainer of the Assist position for incoming Fine Art Photography Cast Members.
- Responsible for providing numerous quality photographs without retouching while managing time within 20-minute mini portrait sessions.

ADAM ALCANTARA PRODUCTIONS

Creative Director | July 2012 - February 2018

- Photographed concerts nationwide, including venues like Red Rocks Amphitheater.
- Created a social media marketing campaign for "1964"...The Tribute's performance at Carnegie Hall.
- Had work published in books, Playbill, New York Magazine, and Modern Drummer
- Created a nationally and internationally aired television campaign for "1964"...The Tribute.

ARKAY-WALKER INCORPORATED

Sales and Information Technology | March 2012 - January 2016

- Facilitated a migration from a Windows platform to an Apple platform, installing and maintaining the computer equipment.
- Executed the installation of Intuit Quickbooks as primary accounting software.
- Trained the staff in using the computers, printers, and Intuit Quickbooks
- Worked as the company's lead graphic designer, designing print ads and assisting with the creation of sales promotions.
- Answered phone calls concerning material safety and application questions, and took customer orders.